Guide to the Naegele Outdoor Records, 1985-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Naegele Outdoor records 1985-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Naegele Outdoor.
1.2 linear feet Extent: 600 Items
Naegele Outdoor Advertising Inc. was a billboard and outdoor advertising company. It was bought by Morris Communications Corp. in 1985, and subsequently renamed Fairway Outdoor Advertising in 1991. The majority of the collection consists of slides with photographs of billboards and other outdoor advertising by Naegele Outdoor in the late 1980s. The collection also includes some printed materials, such as rates and coverages books for the eastern United States. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00928
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Naegele Outdoor Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010.
Historical Note
Naegele Outdoor Advertising began in 1934 as an electric sign business, but was converted by founder Robert Naegele to a billboard business following World War II. Originally based in Richfield, Minnesota, the company quickly grew and acquired other smaller outdoor advertising companies throughout the 1950s and 1960s. It specialized in single-pole billboard designs.
Naegele operated divisions throughout the United States, with headquarters in Minnesota and Florida. During the 1980s, it was frequently involved in litigation as the company challenged local sign ordinances prohibiting or restricting the use of billboards. It lost its lawsuit against the City of Durham, North Carolina, in 1988.
Morris Communications Corporate Family purchased Naegele Outdoor in 1985, intending for it to become the outdoor advertising subsidary. Several Naegele divisions were sold and operated independently for a few years, but it appears that they were subsequently purchased by other outdoor advertising agencies. The name, Naegele Outdoor Advertising, was maintained by Morris until 1991, when it was changed to Fairway Outdoor Advertising. Headquarted in Greenville, South Carolina, Fairway continues to own and operate billboards and other outdoor advertisements throughout the Southeast and Midwest.
Collection Overview
The majority of the collection consists of slides with photographs of billboards and other outdoor advertising by Naegele Outdoor in the late 1980s. Subjects include restaurants, food and drink, sports, housing and home furnishing, and media outlets. The collection also includes some promotional print materials from Naegele, such as rates and coverages books for the eastern United States.
Subject Headings
Naegele Outdoor Advertising Inc.; Advertising, Outdoor -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Signs and signboards -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Billboards -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Color slides
Contents of Collection
- Printed Materials, 1985-1990, (1 box)
  Includes pamphlets and booklets with rates and coverages information for the geographic divisions of Naegele, including Youngstown, Columbus, Des Moines, Greenville, Spartanburg, Asheville, Durham, Raleigh, Indianapolis, Jacksonville, Memphis, Nashville, Minneapolis, New Orleans, and other Southeastern and Midwestern areas. Also includes some copies of Inside Outdoor magazine, order forms for sign construction or repairs, and other miscellaneous items.
  - Poster and billboard order forms, undated (Box 1)
  - Inside Outdoor magazine, 1987-1990 (Box 1)
  - Rates and coverages books, 1986-1990, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Rates and coverages printed pamphlets, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
  - Market summary pamphlets, 1986-1997 (Box 1)
  - Christmas cards and miscellaneous newsletters, 1986 and undated (Box 1)
- Slides, undated, (1 box)
  35mm slides of billboards and outdoor advertisements, arranged alphabetically by subject or content. Dates and locations are unknown.
  - Alcohol (Box 2)
  - Automobile dealerships (Box 2)
  - Cigarettes and smoking (Box 2)
  - Entertainment, recreation, and travel (Box 2)
  - Food and drink (Box 2)
  - Homes (furnishings, decor, heat and air conditioning, entertainment systems) (Box 2)
  - Hospitals, medical and dental care (Box 2)
  - Lodging (hotels, resorts, etc.) (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Native Americans (Box 2)
  - Newspapers and magazines (Box 2)
  - Phone companies (Box 2)
  - Public service and patriotic announcements (Box 2)
  - Radio stations (Box 2)
  - Religion (Box 2)
  - Restaurants (Box 2)
  - Shopping and retail (Box 2)
  - Sporting goods and apparel (Box 2)
  - Sports, fitness, and outdoors (Box 2)